chickensmoothie.com 2019-12-02

# Privacy policy - Chicken Smoothie

This privacy policy describes the kinds of information we collect about users of our website, what uses that information is put to, who has access to the information, and how you can control the use of the information.

This policy may be updated from time to time. The latest version of this policy is visible at https://www.chickensmoothie.com/privacy.php, or by clicking the "privacy policy" link in the footer of our website.

### What information do we collect?

This section describes the kinds of information that we collect about users of our website, and why we collect it.

_Browser information_

  1. The "User-Agent" of your web browser, which usually includes the name and version number of the browser 
  2. Your IP address

This information is used to help us identify the most popular browser versions and regions of the world, so that we can design our service to work properly with those browsers and identify incompatible browsers. 

This information is also used to help us to prevent cheating and abuse, to help protect your account against unauthorised access, and to help you recover a lost account. 

_Cookies_

Our cookies

We use a cookie to keep you logged in as you browse from page to page and to prevent misuse of your account by other users (CSRF protection). If your web browser has cookies disabled, a session-identifier will be added to the end of links within our website for you instead. 

Google Analytics

Google Analytics uses a cookie to help it count how many users are browsing our site and create aggregate browsing statistics. You can [read more details here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245). We don't use any analytics features that would correlate your visits with Google Ads or your Chicken Smoothie account. 

Google Adverts

Our Google Adverts use a cookie for statistics and to avoid you seeing the same advert over and over again. 

Outside the EU, Google will also use the cookie to show you adverts that are relevant to your browsing on other websites. You can turn this off on [Google's Ad Settings page](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). 

For visitors from inside the EU, we have disabled personalised adverts. 

Please see [Google's advert privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) for more details. 

_Account information_

  1. The nickname that you choose for your account.
  2. The email address that you nominate for your account.
  3. If you choose one, an avatar to represent your account.
  4. If you choose to provide it, a description of your interests and a signature to be displayed on your posts. 
  5. Recorded login attempts.

Your email address is used to secure access to your account and to allow your password to be reset if you ever forget it. 

We also use your email address to send you notifications about new events on your account, such as new private messages, new trades, and new posts in topics you have subscribed to. We don't use your email address for marketing or newsletters. 

If you provide them, your interests, signature and avatar are displayed in your public profile. 

Login attempts are recorded in order to allow us to secure access to your account and assist you in recovering it should you forget your password. 

_Birthdates_

Birthdates are collected during signup to allow us to comply with [COPPA regulations](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Children%27s_Online_Privacy_Protection_Act). These are stored encrypted on a separate secure system. Administrators and Admin Assistants have access to birthdates to assist you with recovering lost accounts. 

_Pets_

  1. The names chosen for your pets.
  2. The names chosen for your pet groups.
  3. Your trading history.

Your pet collection is public to allow you to show your pet collection to your friends.

Your trading history is used to help detect cheating and resolve trading disputes between members.

_Forum_

  1. Posts and topics created on the forum by your account.
  2. Private messages sent from your account.

Posts and topics made on the forum allow you to communicate with other users.

Private messages are recorded to allow disputes between members to be settled by administrators and to prevent verbal attacks between members.

### Who has access to the information?

_Browser information_

Browser information is only visible to admins and admin assistants.

IP addresses which are recorded for public forum actions are visible to both administrators and moderators.

IP addresses recorded for other actions are only visible to admins and admin assistants.

_Account information_

Your email address is only visible to admins and admin assistants.

Login attempts are only visible to admins and admin assistants. Your password is securely stored and cannot be viewed by any staff member.

If you provide them, your interests, signature and avatar are publicly visible.

_Pets_

Your pet collection is public.

Your trading history is only visible to your account and to administrators.

_Forum_

Posts and topics made on the forum are public.

Private messages are visible to your account, accounts that you send messages to, and to administrators. They are also visible to moderators if a person that you send a private message to makes a complaint about that conversation.

We may additionally disclose information (including personal information) to prevent misuse of our website, to enforce our site rules, to protect or defend our rights and property or protect the safety and security of our visitors or others, or if we are legally required to do so by the appropriate authorities.

### Where is the information stored?

The information is stored in Amazon's United States datacenters. Our website backups are stored there and also mirrored offsite.

### How is the information protected?

Our database is protected by firewalls and Amazon's secure access controls. Offsite backups are encrypted and protected by firewalls and antivirus.

### How can I control the use of my information?

All of the personal information about your account, including your nickname, public profile, private messages, login records, personal information included in your pet collection and trades (e.g. logged IP addresses), browser information, email address, posts and forum topics can be deleted from our database on request. In the case of forum posts and topics, please contact a moderator using the Help system or by clicking the Report button on the forum post you want removed. Otherwise, please contact an administrator at [coppa@chickensmoothie.com](mailto:coppa@chickensmoothie.com). 

You can request us to give you a copy of the personal data we hold about your account by emailing [coppa@chickensmoothie.com](mailto:coppa@chickensmoothie.com). 

### Who can I contact?

If you have any questions or concerns about privacy, please contact us using these details:

Privacy Manager, ChickenSmoothie.com  
2 Gresham Street  
Tainui 9013  
Dunedin  
New Zealand
